

Adam Beeson

Summary

Application development professional with over 15 years of enterprise application development. Skilled in technical problem solving, architecture and design, and team leadership.

Professional Details Location

Denver, CO USA

Contact

+1.719.214.2446

adam@adambeeson.net

Random Facts

- Avid Snowboarder
- Constant learner (Pluralsight, Udemy, MSDN, Blogs and Podcasts)
- Amateur world-traveler
- Cooking Enthusiast

Professional Experience

Software Architect
Nelnet, Inc.

2015-Current

Software Architecture (Design, Standards Framing, Roadmapping and Implementation) for building Financial Technology Enterprise Applications. Team lead for multiple delivery teams.

Architecture & Design - C# - NodeJS/Typescript - AWS Angular 14 - Postgres - Team Leading/Mentorship

Senior Software Developer
Compassion Intl (contract)

2014-2015

Full Stack developer building angularJS and .NET MVC applications used around the world. Wrote backend microservices for an IOS application.

C# - dotnet core 2x - MVC - AngularJS - SQL - MongoDB - Redis

Senior Software Developer Veteran's Engineering

2014

Full stack developer building front end applications and back end services for US Army training applications.

C# - ASP.NET - MVC - AngularJS - SQL

Software Developer
 Assar Points Medical (

AspenPointe Medical Services

2012-2014

Full stack developer working on WebForm and MVC call center (dashboard) applications.

C# - ASP.NET - MVC - SQL

 Software Developer Northrop Grumman Corp.

2007-2012

Full Stack developer working on training software for the USAF and US Navy, written in C#, VB.NET.

C# - ASP.NET - SQL - VB.NET

Education

Computer Information Systems
 Colorado State University - Pueblo

2007

Hard Skills

Object Oriented Programming Software Architecture NodeJS Typescript SQL

Cloud Architecture (AWS) .NET/dotnetcore TFS Git Github Gitlab CI/CD

Soft Skills

Public Speaking Leadership Mentoring Developer Advocacy SDLC Mastery